<task id="_bmad/sos/tasks/morals-check.xml" name="Morals Violation Check">
  <objective>Quick check against the 7 Inviolable Morals — HARD STOP on any violation</objective>

  <inputs>
    <input name="content" desc="The artifact or concept to check for moral violations" />
  </inputs>

  <llm critical="true">
    <i>MANDATORY: Execute ALL steps in exact order</i>
    <i>Morals are ABSOLUTE — there is no negotiation, no gray area</i>
    <i>Any violation is a HARD STOP requiring immediate Response Protocol</i>
    <i>Load morals from {project-root}/_bmad/sos/data/divine-morals-7.csv</i>
  </llm>

  <flow>
    <step n="1" title="Load Morals Framework">
      <action>Load divine-morals-7.csv for violation indicators and enforcement</action>
    </step>

    <step n="2" title="Seven Morals Check" critical="true">
      <action>Check each moral — CLEAR / WARNING / VIOLATION:
        1. Never Deceive — Any misleading content, hidden agendas, or dishonesty?
        2. Never Exploit — Any extraction without reciprocity, leveraging vulnerability?
        3. Never Coerce — Any forced compliance, manipulation, or pressure?
        4. Never Exclude — Any discrimination, gatekeeping, or exclusion?
        5. Never Desecrate — Any profaning of sacred spaces, practices, or nature?
        6. Never Betray — Any breaking of trust, broken promises, or disloyalty?
        7. Never Stagnate — Any resistance to growth, clinging to outdated patterns?
      </action>
      <action>If ANY VIOLATION found: IMMEDIATELY flag as HARD STOP</action>
    </step>

    <step n="3" title="Present Results">
      <action>If all CLEAR: Present clean moral standing</action>
      <action>If WARNINGS: Present areas needing attention, recommend Gentle Correction</action>
      <action>If VIOLATIONS: HARD STOP — present violation clearly, recommend Response Protocol level, do not proceed with any other reviews until resolved</action>
    </step>
  </flow>

  <halt-conditions>
    <condition>HALT if no content is provided to evaluate</condition>
    <condition>HARD STOP if any moral violation is detected — do not continue</condition>
  </halt-conditions>
</task>
